geniatech.eu 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy | Geniatech EyeTV

### 2\. Collection and saving the personal data and nature and purpose of its use

 _When visiting the website_

If you use the website www.geniatech.eu purely for information purposes, i.e. you do not register or send us any other information, the browser used on your device automatically sends information to our website server. This information is saved temporarily in what is known as a log file. The following information is recorded without you doing anything and saved until it is deleted automatically:

  * IP address of the querying computer,
  * Date and time of access,
  * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT),
  * Name and URL file accessed,
  * Access status/HTTP status code,
  * Volume of data transferred,
  * Website from which you accessed our site (referrer URL),
  * Browser used,
  * Operating system on your computer and its interface,
  * Name of your access provider,
  * Browser software language and version.

This data is processed by us for the following purposes:

  * To guarantee a seamless connection is established to the website,
  * To guarantee user-friendly use of the website,
  * To evaluate system security and stability
  * and for other administrative purposes.

The legal basis for this data-processing is article 6, para. 1, clause 1, letter f, GDPR. The purposes of the data collection above are based on our justified interests. Under no circumstances will we use data collected to derive information about you.

When you visit our website, we also use cookies and analysis services. We make a distinction between cookies which are technically necessary and those which are for the purposes of statistical recording and optimisation. The latter are used only if you have consented to this. You can find more details about this in sections 4 and 5 of this privacy policy.

 _If you subscribe to our newsletter_

If you have provided explicit consent in accordance with art. 6, para 1, clause 1, letter a GDPR, we use your email address to send you our newsletter on a regular basis. Entering an email address is sufficient to receive the newsletter. Entering further data marked as separate is voluntary, and this data is used to provide more targeted information.

You can unsubscribe at any time, for example, using the link at the end of every newsletter. Alternatively, you can send a request to unsubscribe by email at any time to datenschutz@eu-geniatech.com.

 _If you use our contact/support or complaint form_

If you have any questions or support requests, or in the event of a complaint, we offer you the option of making contact with us through the forms provided on the website. This requires you to provide at least a valid e-mail address, so we know who the question comes from and we can respond. As a rule, further information can be provided on a voluntary basis. Further information is required for support requests and complaints.

Data processing for the purposes of making contact with us is in accordance with art. 6, para 1, clause 1, letter a GDPR on the basis of the consent you have provided voluntarily, or in accordance with art. 6, para 1, clause 1, letter b GDPR for support requests or complaints.

The personal data collected by us for the use of the relevant forms is automatically deleted once your enquiry has been resolved.

 _If you use our web shop_

If you wish to place an order in our web shop, you need to provide personal data in order for us to process your order and conclude a contract. The mandatory information required to process the contracts is marked separately, further information is voluntary. We process the data provided by you in order to execute your order. To do this, we may forward your payment information to our company bank. The legal basis for this is article 6, para. 1, clause 1, letter b, GDPR.

You have the option of creating a customer account, which allows us to save your data for further purchases in the future. If you create an account under “My Account”, the data you provide is saved on a revocable basis. All further data, including your user account, can be deleted in the customer area at any time.

We can also process the data provided by you in order to inform you about other interesting products in our portfolio or send you emails with technical information.

Business and tax law regulations stipulate that we must save your address, payment and order data for a period of ten years. However, after two years, processing is restricted such that your data is only used in order to comply with the statutory regulations.

In order to prevent unauthorised access by third parties to your personal data, especially your financial data, the order process is encrypted using TLS technology.

Of course, you can object to your personal data being used for advertising and data analysis purposes when using our web shop at any time. You can use the contact details above to inform us if you no longer wish to receive advertising: datenschutz@eu-geniatech.com

 _If you use further functions and services on our website_

As well as using our website for information only, and the newsletter and forms options, we offer various services which you can use if you are interested. To do this, you generally need to enter further personal data which we require and use to provide the relevant service.

Sometimes, we use external service providers to process your data. They have been carefully selected and commissioned by us, are bound by our instructions and are regularly checked.

We can also pass your personal data on to third parties where we are offering promotions, competitions, contracts or similar services in conjunction with partners. You can find more detailed information on this when you provide your personal data or in the small print at the bottom of the service description.

If our service provider or partner has their headquarters in a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA), we will inform you of the consequence of these circumstances in the description of the offer.

If you have provided consent to the processing of your data when using further functions and offers on our website, you can revoke this at any time. Once expressed to us, this revocation has an impact on our rights to process your personal data.

If our processing of your personal data for the use of further functions and offers on our website relies on weighing up interests, you can submit an objection to this processing. This applies especially if the processing is not required for the fulfilment of the contract with you, which we will always highlight in the following description of the functions. If you do revoke your consent in this way, we ask you to set out your reasons why we may not process your personal data in the ways we have described. If your objection is justified, we will check the situation and either discontinue or modify data processing or set out to you the binding proprietary reasons for which we are continuing with the processing.

Of course, you can object to your personal data from the use of further functions and offers on our website being used for advertising and data analysis purposes at any time. You can use the contact details above to inform us if you no longer wish to receive advertising: datenschutz@eu-geniatech.com
